<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on less on sec</title><link>https://lessonsec.com/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on less on sec</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 18:06:36 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lessonsec.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The art of lock picking: Insights from picking locks</title><link>https://lessonsec.com/posts/the-art-of-lock-picking-insights-from-picking-locks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 18:06:36 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://lessonsec.com/posts/the-art-of-lock-picking-insights-from-picking-locks/</guid><description>Lock picking is the practice of unlocking a lock by manipulating the components of the lock device without the original key. - Wikipedia
Locks are an universal item used to secure everything from homes and offices to critical infrastructures. They often represent the first line of security an attacker will have to face while trying to reach a target.
Although lock picking is often associated with criminal intent, it can also be an essential skill within penetration testers.</description><content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p><strong>Lock picking</strong> is the practice of unlocking a lock by manipulating the components of the lock device without the original key. - <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lock_picking">Wikipedia</a></p>
</blockquote>
<p>Locks are an universal item used to secure everything from homes and offices to critical infrastructures. They often represent the first line of security an attacker will have to face while trying to reach a target.</p>
<p>Although lock picking is often associated with criminal intent, it can also be an essential skill within penetration testers. Like any other red team technique, lock picking translates to a defensive skill as it assists with finding and patching vulnerabilities. Since locks play such an important role in modern day security, it is important as a security professional to understand the lock picking process and what comes with it.</p>
<h3 id="lock-picking-is-hacking">Lock picking is hacking</h3>
<p>Picking locks is not so different from hacking a computer: you are faced with a challenge and need to defeat security measures to get to the target. In both cases to succeed, you will need a strong background of study and practice.
The passion for discovering vulnerabilities and the curiosity to learn about a technology is the reason why lock picking is so popular amongst security professionals.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>It’s another version of hacking. Hacking is all about using a system against itself, or bypassing a system by thinking outside of the box. Lockpicking is almost like a magic trick, a puzzle of the same sort. You can’t bypass it without using the lock’s systems exactly how they were meant to be used or by using it in a manner the creators never expected it to be used. - <a href="https://twitter.com/HydeNS33k">Jek Hyde</a></p>
</blockquote>
<p>While the technical knowledge received from practicing lock picking is useful, picking locks may be one of the least effective ways to enter inside a protected perimeters. This can be true for many reasons:</p>
<ul>
<li>Some locks can be <em>really hard</em> to pick open</li>
<li>Picking locks can take a <em>really long</em> time</li>
<li>Bypassing doors and locks is usually a more effective approach</li>
<li>Social engineering oftentimes works better</li>
</ul>
<p>While <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=LRXGIdg7eNE">lock picking has it&rsquo;s applications</a>, it remains an impractical technique for numerous situations. This then leads to the question: <em>why practice lock picking</em>?
The reason is simple. Lock picking and cybersecurity are similar in nature where the skills can become transferable.</p>
<p>Some skills that can be picked up from picking locks which apply to cybersecurity are:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Outside of the box thinking</strong>
If a lock doesn&rsquo;t want to open, how can you make it do so? The more complex the lock, the more complex the solution can be. Though with the right intuition, you are in.</li>
<li><strong>Think like the enemy</strong>
The only way to secure something is knowing exactly how to defeat its security measures.
Picking locks brings a new dimension to &ldquo;<em>thinking like the enemy</em>&rdquo;, since implications are projected into the physical world.</li>
<li><strong>Ethics</strong>
A strong ethic is needed in both cyber and physical security. Considering different approaches with the same concept can add to an individual&rsquo;s experience.</li>
</ul>
<p>To conclude, lock picking is an important skill that gives a firsthand experience into the world of security. Working on a physical level can assist with understanding the security risk faced every day. <em>It is not possible to improve security without the understanding of how an attacker can defeat security measures that are in place</em>.</p>
]]></content></item></channel></rss>