<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>less on sec</title><link>https://lessonsec.com/</link><description>Recent content on less on sec</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Apr 2021 19:52:32 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lessonsec.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Templating</title><link>https://lessonsec.com/thoughts/templating/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Apr 2021 19:52:32 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://lessonsec.com/thoughts/templating/</guid><description>Discussing with someone on Reddit, I realized that template languages are a powerful tool that can be helpful in many situations.
I&amp;rsquo;ll experiment with Jinja2 and probably use it to improve Intrudo.</description></item><item><title>Smart_card</title><link>https://lessonsec.com/thoughts/smart_card/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Apr 2021 12:13:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://lessonsec.com/thoughts/smart_card/</guid><description>Did you know that SIM cards have a processor and host a VM?
Here&amp;rsquo;s an interesting overview on smart cards.
It shows the components, how they work and the security mechanisms in use.
There&amp;rsquo;s also a a brief analysis on how to attack them, both via software and physically.
https://opensecuritytraining.info/SmartCards_files/SmartCards.pdf</description></item><item><title>Dev Chronicles: Creating an HTTP attack client</title><link>https://lessonsec.com/posts/dev-chronicles-creating-an-http-attack-client/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 23:23:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://lessonsec.com/posts/dev-chronicles-creating-an-http-attack-client/</guid><description>Intrudo is a tool for automating customized attacks against web applications loosely shaped after burp intruder.
Check it out: https://github.com/0xless/Intrudo
A little of background While working on CTFs I would usually write a bunch of lines of python to automate attacks, it worked fine, but I felt like I needed to improve my workflow. So I decided to learn new approaches and strengthen my use of commercial offensive tools.
I have used burp suite in the past, but I have not taken the time to explore it thoroughly, so I figured the best way to do that would be the labs that PortSwigger created for this reason.</description></item><item><title>Whoami</title><link>https://lessonsec.com/whoami/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lessonsec.com/whoami/</guid><description>Hi, I&amp;rsquo;m less (Matteo). I&amp;rsquo;m a Computer scientist and cybersecurity enthusiast. I see hacking as a tool to learn new things and I’ve always been fascinated by breaking stuff.
Of course I&amp;rsquo;m invested in software hacking, but I also enjoy exploring hardware and physical security.
I often go too deep into technology related &amp;ldquo;rabbit holes&amp;rdquo;, this blog was born so I can share my experiences and get motivated to finish what I started!</description></item><item><title>Chunked</title><link>https://lessonsec.com/thoughts/chunked/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 18:07:12 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://lessonsec.com/thoughts/chunked/</guid><description>Was working on something and got curious about the chunked transfer encoding, in particular about the fact that HTTP headers could be defined after the body of the request. Dug a bit deeper and found out it&amp;rsquo;s actually a known attack vector! Check this for more: https://swende.se/blog/HTTPChunked.html</description></item><item><title>The art of lock picking: Insights from picking locks</title><link>https://lessonsec.com/posts/the-art-of-lock-picking-insights-from-picking-locks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 18:06:36 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://lessonsec.com/posts/the-art-of-lock-picking-insights-from-picking-locks/</guid><description>Lock picking is the practice of unlocking a lock by manipulating the components of the lock device without the original key. - Wikipedia
Locks are an universal item used to secure everything from homes and offices to critical infrastructures. They often represent the first line of security an attacker will have to face while trying to reach a target.
Although lock picking is often associated with criminal intent, it can also be an essential skill within penetration testers.</description></item><item><title>Rake</title><link>https://lessonsec.com/thoughts/rake/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Feb 2021 11:19:19 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://lessonsec.com/thoughts/rake/</guid><description>Raking is not really my first choice when it comes to covert entry: it&amp;rsquo;s easy to spot with forensic analysis and it only really works with low to moderate security locks. It can be the fastest and best choice for many situations nonetheless. That said, I bumped into this: https://elvencraft.com/lpd/Raking%20Techniques.html
Awesome material on raking techniques.</description></item><item><title>Http_test</title><link>https://lessonsec.com/thoughts/http_test/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2021 11:25:19 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://lessonsec.com/thoughts/http_test/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on a project and discovered https://httpbin.org/.
Great tool to test and experiment with HTTP.</description></item><item><title>Bypass PHP addslashes()</title><link>https://lessonsec.com/thoughts/sqli_charset/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2021 12:03:55 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://lessonsec.com/thoughts/sqli_charset/</guid><description>So I was working on a CTF and had to try to perform an SQLi through a PHP page on an addslashes() sanitized text field. Turns out the flaw was in a business logic and I was looking in the wrong spot, but I found this interesting article on bypassing this sanitization mechanism abusing GBK character encoding: https://shiflett.org/blog/2006/addslashes-versus-mysql-real-escape-string</description></item><item><title>Hello_world</title><link>https://lessonsec.com/thoughts/hello_world/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 18:19:43 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://lessonsec.com/thoughts/hello_world/</guid><description>This is the very first content on this website, I guess I&amp;rsquo;m expected to say hello world!</description></item></channel></rss>